大家好  感恩节快乐  嘘嘘
Hey, everybody. Happy Thanksgiving. Shh.
不让大家知道  今年有感恩节吗
What, are we keeping Thanksgiving a secret this year?
不是  我们正在玩一个游戏
No, we're playing this game I learned at work.
你要在六分钟内  写出美国各州州名
You have to name all the states in six minutes.
这个啊   太容易了
What? That's, like, insanely easy.
事实上这个游戏很难   你总是会漏掉一个
No, it's harder than it sounds. You always forget at least one.
某些人会漏掉  十四个
Or in some cases, 14.
这太蠢了  我没有跟任何人玩
It's a stupid game and I wasn't playing against other people...
所以技术上来说我没输
...so technically, I didn't lose.
你忘了十四州的州名
You forgot 14 states?
没有人在乎南北达科他州
Nobody cares about the Dakotas.
好了  时间到
Oh, okay, time's up.
好了  我写出四十八州
All right, I got 48.
还不错  菲比呢
Oh, that's not bad. Pheebs?
我厌倦写州名   所以决定写出各种芹菜的名字
Oh, I got tired of naming states, so I decided to list the types of celery.
我写了一个  普通芹菜
And I have one, regular celery.
好   瑞秋写出四十八州   菲比在蔬菜名称方面
Okay, so Rachel's got 48 and Phoebe has the lead in...
称霸  乔伊呢
...vegetables. Joey?
跟钱德的愚蠢州名游戏新冠军打声招呼吧
Say hello to the new champ of Chandler's dumb states game.
哇   你写了几个   五十六个
Wow, how many you got? Fifty-six.
老友记  第七季  第8集  钱德不爱狗
Friends S07E08  The One Where Chandler Doesn't Like Dogs
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
新英格兰为什么不是一个州
Hey, how is New England not a state?
他们有运动代表队
Huh? They have a sports team.
南奥勒冈有运动代表队吗
Does South Oregon have a sports team?
对啦
There you go.
为什么多了一付餐具
How come we have one extra place setting?
你邀了你的助理过来  对了  抱歉  秦格不来了
Because you invited your assistant. Oh, right, sorry. Tag's not coming.
他女朋友来了  所以他得去陪她
His girlfriend came into town, so he's spending Thanksgiving with her.
你为什么没有告诉我
Oh, why didn't you tell me'?
我帮他做了专属的  番薯酿南瓜
I made him his own individual sweet potato stuffed pumpkin.
我本来想说   但我想
Oh, well, I was going to, but then I figured, you know...
你做的菜既好吃  又好看
...your food is so delicious and perfect...
我想多吃一点你做的南瓜
...you can never have too many of those pumpkin things.
你这话太假了  你以为我会相信  不过我还是觉得听着很高兴
You'd think I wouldn't enjoy that because it is so fake, ha, ha, but I still do.
普通芹菜
Regular celery.
我已经写了
Oh, I already have that.
好了  时间还剩下很多
Done, with time to spare.
这可能是新世界记录   我讨厌对你们说教
Ooh, this may be a new world's record. You know, I hate to lecture you guys...
但这真的是太丢脸了  一群受过良好教育的成年人
...but it's kind of disgraceful that a group of well-educated adults...
跟乔伊  无法写出全部的州名
...and Joey, can't name all the states.
你们看过地图  或是圆圆的色彩鲜艳叫做"地球仪"的东西吗
You ever see a map or one of those round colorful things called a globe?
麦哲伦先生  你只答对了四十六州
Uh, Magellan? You got 46 states.
什么   不可能   四十六州
What? That's impossible. Forty-six.
那个受过良好教育  写不出剩下十州州名的人是谁
Well, who's well-educated now, Mr. I-Forgot-Ten-States?
烤箱太满了  我要借乔伊的烤箱
I'm out of oven space. I'm gonna go turn on Joey's.
拜托   看好他   别让乔伊偷吃东西
Please, watch him. Do not let Joey eat any of the food.
我只有一个人
I am only one man.
好了   时间到   再给我1分钟
Okay, time is up. Give me another minute.
如果现在想不出来   你永远都想不出来   好吗
Ross, if you don't know them by now, you will never know them, okay?
那就是这个游戏好玩的地方   它会让你想要杀了自己
That is the beauty of this game. It makes you want to kill yourself.
太疯狂了   我一定答得出来
This is crazy. I can do this.
好吧   我敢说我能在晚饭前写出五十个州的州名
All right, uh, I bet I can get all 50, uh, before dinner.
好吧   但你写不出来就不能吃晚饭
Okay, but if you can't, no dinner.
就这么说定了
You're on.
别偷看我的答案   里面有很多你写不出来的州名
All right, don't look at my list, because there's a lot on there that you don't have.
你知道你的烤箱坏了吗
Hey, did you guys know your oven doesn't work?
可装满外送菜单的抽屉   没坏吧
But the drawer full of takeout menus is okay, right?
罗斯   我要借用你的烤箱
Ross, I'm gonna use yours, okay? Shh.
钱德   快来帮我
Chandler, give me a hand.
乔伊   别让罗斯偷看地图或你家的地球仪
Sure. Joey, do not let Ross look at any maps or the globe in your apartment.
别担心   那又不是美国的地球仪
Don't worry, Chandler. It's not a globe of the United States.
嘿   我要去散个步
Hey, you guys, I'm gonna go out and take a walk.
菲比  你的包包为什么在动
Phoebe, why is your bag moving?
没有啊   它真的在动
Oh, it's not. Seriously, it's moving.
里面装了什么东西   就是我编织的东西而已
What the hell's in there?  It's just my knitting. That's all.
对   我织了这个
Yes, I knit this.
我真的很厉害
I'm very good.
罗斯的公寓很漂亮  为什么我们从不来这里混
Ross' apartment is nice. Why don't we hang out here more often?
我不知道   或许是因为它有个怪味道
I don't know. Maybe because it smells weird.
有点像是放了很久的南瓜味
It's like old pumpkins or something.
那是我的派   这个味道好香
That's my pie. Which smells delicious.
哇啊哦  怎么了
Uh-oh. Uh-oh. What?
我们让乔伊跟食物独处了
We left Joey alone with the food.
没错   我就知道
Yep, yep, I knew it.
他在
There he is...
拿馅料喂小狗吃
...feeding stuffing to a dog.
你好  这里是盖勒及宾的家  有什么事吗
Hi, Geller-Bing residence. How can I help?
菲比   为什么我们家会有狗
Phoebe, why is there a dog in our apartment?
对不起   你是谁
I'm sorry, who's this?
菲比  有只狗坐在我的沙发上
Phoebe, there's a dog sitting on my couch.
告诉她我对狗过敏   我会告诉她的
Tell her I'm allergic, and I will sue.
这里没有狗  不  真的有
No, there's no dog here. Yes There is.
他是黑白相间   而且毛很长
He's black and white and shaggy.
他就坐在瑞秋旁边  正在舔她的手
He's sitting next to Rachel and licking Rachel's hand.
我的天啊   你在哪里
Oh, my God. Where are you?
我马上回去
I'll be right there.
他们已经回来了  怎么这么快啊
They're here already? How are they doing this?
嗨  泰格  你来这里做什么
Hi, Tag. What are you doing here?
我想知道你的邀请   是不是还有效
I, uh, wanted to see if your offer to spend Thanksgiving with you was still good.
当然有效   快进来吧
Well, sure. Come in.
你女朋友呢
Well, what happened to your girlfriend?
今天早上我们分手了
We, uh, kind of broke up this morning.
我很遗憾   所以她回俄亥俄去了
Oh, I'm sorry. Yeah, so she went back to Ohio.
俄亥俄州  谢谢你
Ohio, thank you.
狗在哪里
Huh. Where's the dog?
什么狗  这里没有狗
What dog? There's no dog here.
那只狗离开了
Yeah, that dog left.
菲比
Phoebe.
菲比   快开门
Phoebe, open up.
房间里没有狗
There's no dog in here.
菲比   我们听到了狗叫声了
Phoebe, we can hear the dog barking.
不   那只是我的咳嗽声
No, that's just me coughing.
很好  你们回来了
Oh, good. There you are.
听着  我房间里有只狗
Listen, urn, I have a dog in my room.
他在这里做什么
What is it doing here?
我帮我朋友照顾他   他们有事出城去了
I'm watching it for friends who went out of town.
等一下
Wait.
嗨  我是克朗克
Hello, my name is Klunkers.
我可以跟你们这些大好人住在一起吗
May I please stay with you nice people?
我也希望能留他住下来   但钱德对狗过敏
Oh, I wish he could stay here, but Chandler's allergic.
我对狗严重过敏   好吗
Extremely allergic, okay?
只要我一靠近狗   超过五分钟
If I am anywhere near a dog for more than five minutes...
我的喉咙就会紧缩
...my throat will just close up.
真是奇怪   这只狗在这里住了三天
That's odd, because this dog's been living here for the past three days.
真的吗
Really?
如果他在这里住了那么久
If the dog has been here that long...
你一点反应都没有   或许你对他不会过敏
...and you haven't had a reaction, maybe you're not allergic to this dog.
他还是得离开   好吗
Well, it still has to go, right?
为什么
Why?
好吧   我   别那么做
Okay, it's, um-Don't do it.
别做什么   我非说不可
Don't do what? I have to.
好吗   时间到了
Okay? It's time.
好吧   我讨厌狗
Okay, I hate dogs.
什么   太疯狂了  为什么
What? That's crazy. Why?
我早跟你说过了
Told you.
他们很黏人
They are needy...
爱乱跳   你不知道他们在想什么
...they are jumpy, and you can't tell what they are thinking...
那样子把我吓得半死
...and that scares me a little bit.
你说的对  他们很可怕
You're right. They are scary. Aah!
他吃掉了放在我手上的点心
She just ate a treat out of my hand!
等一下  你不喜欢所有的狗   连小狗都不喜欢吗
Wait a minute. Do you not like all dogs? I mean, not even puppies?
这里有小狗吗
Is there a puppy here?
你不喜欢小狗  喂  你是新来的
You don't like puppies? Okay, you are new.
听着   钱德   我跟你说过  别跟其他人说你不喜欢狗
Look, Chandler, I told you. Never tell anyone about this dog thing.
这就像罗斯不喜欢冰淇淋一样
It's like Ross not liking ice cream.
你不喜欢冰淇淋   它太冰了
You don't like ice cream? It's too cold.
狗也让我觉得很不舒服
Okay, it's just that dogs make me a little uncomfortable.
我的牙齿冰得好痛
Hurts my teeth.
我不想这么说   不希望你们讨厌我
I don't wanna say this. I don't want you guys to hate me...
但我不喜欢这只狗  待在我身边  好吗
...but, uh, I don't think I can be around that dog anymore, okay?
不是那只狗走   就是我走
So either the dog goes or I go. Huh.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我怎么可能答不出来
How can I not get this?
我是大学教授  SAT了考了1450分
I'm a college professor. I got 1450 on my SATs.
是1250分才对
Twelve fifty.
该死   我忘了你在这里
Damn, I forgot you were here.
好吧  我们得把克朗克送到罗斯家
All right. We're gonna take Klunkers to Ross'.
马上就回来
We'll be back in a minute.
等一下  你们离开前  我能问你们一个问题吗
Oh, wait, before you go, can I ask a question?
如果一个男人跟女朋友分手了
Um, when a guy breaks up with his girlfriend...
我得等多久才能采取行动
...what is an appropriate amount of time to wait before you make a move?
我想是一个月
Oh, I'd say about a month.
真的吗   我觉得是三到四个月  半小时
Really? I'd say three to four. Half-hour.
真有趣
Interesting.
但他是你的助理   我劝你别那么做
When it's your assistant, I would say never.
好了   瑞秋  问题是他喜欢你吗
All right, Rach, the big question is, does he like you?
如果他不喜欢你   这样做只是在对牛放屁
Right? Because if he doesn't like you, this is all a moo point.
对牛 "放屁"
Huh. A "moo" point?
对  牛不知道你做了什么
Yeah. It's like a cow's opinion.
那不重要
It just doesn't matter.
那是在 "放屁"
It's "moo."
是我跟他同居太久   还是他的话真的有道理
Have I been living with him for too long, or did that all just make sense?
别听乔伊的   好吗   看看他的样子
Please don't listen to Joey. Okay? Would you look at him?
他很沮丧   家人又不在身边
He's obviously depressed. He's away from his family.
他在跟陌生人过感恩节
He's spending Thanksgiving with strangers.
现在他需要你这个朋友
What he needs right now is for you to be his friend.
你说的对  对不起  谢谢
Oh, you're right. I'm sorry. Thank you.
好吧  我会那么做的  很好  照她们的话去做
Okay, that's what I'm going to do. Fine, take their advice.
反正没有人会听我的话
No one ever listens to me.
只要包装好看  没有人会在乎内容
When the package is this pretty, no one cares what's inside.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
你还好吧
How you holding up?
还可以  是吗
Not bad. Yeah?
关于你女朋友的事我很遗憾   谢谢
I'm sorry about your girlfriend. Thanks.
你们在一起很久了吗   一年了  总是分分合合的
Were you guys together a long time? A year, on and off.
我以为我们会相守一生   现在我不会那么想了
I thought we'd end up together. I don't anymore.
因为她跟你分手了   对
Now that she broke up with you. Yeah.
这真的很奇怪
Hmm. It's weird.
我以前总以为我会遇见一个人  坠入爱河  过着幸福的生活
I always used to assume that I would meet someone and fall in love and be happy.
好像很自然而然  最近我会想如果不是那样呢
That all that was just a given. Well, lately, it's like, what if it's not?
你有那种感觉吗
Do you ever have that feeling?
不
No.
有
Yeah.
我常有那种感觉  一直都有  真的很可怕
All the time. Constantly. It's terrifying.
但后来我想通了  一定会发生的
But, you know, then I figure it has to work out.
为什么
Why?
因为一定会的
Because it has to.
你真的什么都知道  对吧  没错  我真的什么都知道
You have all the answers, don't you? Yeah, I know, I do. I really do.
谢谢你陪我聊  别这样  这不是上司的工作吗
Hey, thanks for talking to me. Come on, what are bosses for?
快来抱一下吧
Hug it out.
好了  他也喜欢你
All right, he likes you back.
我说过你该表白的
Huh? Told you you should go for it.
什么
What?
下面的噪音有没有盖过那句话
Street noise drown any of that out?
没有吗  待会见  好吧
No? All right, I'll see you later. Ha, ha. Okay.
刚刚乔伊说了什么   我也喜欢你
What did Joey say? I like you back?
你知道的   他
Uh, yeah-You know, well, see, he...
乔伊知道  我对我的背没信心
Joey knows that I'm very insecure about my back.
刚刚你在抱我
And... And you were hugging me...
很明显地   你不讨厌它   没错
...so obviously you are not repulsed by it. Yeah. Heh.
等一下   那样根本说不通
Wait a minute, that doesn't make any sense.
是吗
No?
好吧   事实是这样的
All right, here's the truth. Ahem.
乔伊会那么说
Joey said what he said because, urn...
因为我被你吸引
...I'm attracted to you.
对   我承认
Wow. Yeah, I admit it.
我暗恋你  我知道那很疯狂  因为我们是同事
I have a crush on you. And, uh, I know that's crazy because we work together...
我们之间不该发生任何事
...and nothing could ever happen.
我一点都不想吓到你
And the last thing I wanted to do was freak you out...
或是让你觉得不自在
...or make you feel uncomfortable.
所以我认为  你最好快说句话
Which is why it would be really great if you said something right about now.
我的天啊   那些家伙在偷我的车
Oh, my God. Those guys are stealing my car.
什么   就在那边   那是我的车
What? Right there. That's my car.
嘿   好了  他们得花点时间
Hey! Okay, that's gonna take a minute.
你有话要跟我说吗
Do you have anything else you wanna get off your chest?
我不敢相信
I can't believe this.
我们还有时间谈   他们还没上车
Wait, we still have time to talk, and they're not even in the car yet.
你看  他们上车了
Oh, look, there they go. Okay.
好了  菲比   或许我们该回去了
Okay, Phoebe. We should probably go back now.
求求你   别离开我   我会很寂寞的
Please, don't leave me. I'll be lonely.
停了  别说了
Stop it. Stop.
我们走吧   我们可以很坚强的   好吧
Okay, let's go. We can be strong. Yeah, okay.
天啊   你听到了吗    他在叫 "摩妮卡"
Oh, my God, did you hear that? She said "Monica."
我不能丢下他
Oh, I can't leave her.
我们可以偷偷把狗带回去  钱德不会发现的
If you want, we could sneak the dog back in and Chandler wouldn't even know.
那样怕是不行的
That's not gonna work.
我把小狗藏在房间里三天了   钱德完全不知道
I had that dog there for three days and Chandler had no idea.
他没有那么聪明
He's not so smart.
嘿  我也不知道
Hey. I didn't know either.
对  但是你觉得怪怪的  对吧
Yeah, but you kind of knew that something was going on, didn't you?
没错   我知道
Yeah, I knew. Heh.
钱德在哪里
Where's Chandler?
我在这里   快去洗手
Here I am. Wash your hands.
你怎么知道
How did you know?
他怎么又回来了
Hey, what's she doing back here?
别激动   罗斯   他不是冰淇淋做的
Relax, Ross. She's not made of ice cream.
听着  菲比  我按照位置将各州州名排好了
Hey, look, Phoebe. I, uh, laid out the states geographically.
没时间谈这事了
No, no, we don't have time for this.
我们不能让钱德靠近我房间
We have to keep Chandler away from my room.
对   但是
Yeah, but, look what I--
所以我们没有时间了
See, this is exactly what we do not have time for.
摩妮卡在哪里  她在菲比房里  你不能进去
Where's Monica? Uh, in Phoebe's room. You can't go in.
为什么
Why not?
摩妮卡在哭
Monica's crying.
关于克朗克的事   她非常难过
She's very upset about this whole Klunkers thing.
我应该进去的  不
Well, I should go in there. No, no.
不   现在她不想见你
No, she doesn't want to see you right now.
为什么   因为你把那只狗赶走了
Why not? Because you sent away the dog.
太可笑了  是吗
That's ridiculous. Oh, is it? Is it?
听着   小时候摩妮卡跟我养了一只狗叫路佛
Look, when Monica and I were kids, we had a dog named Rover.
有一天  我爸决定不再喜欢狗了
And, um, one day, my dad decides he doesn't like dogs.
摩妮卡跟她的朋友菲丽丝
So Monica and her friend...Phyllis...
把狗送走  那是我们最后一次见到他  好吗
...take away the dog, and that was the last time we ever saw him.
你懂吗  这次也一样
Don't you see? This is just like that...
只不过有些细节不一样
...only with a few details changed.
好吧   我换了运动裤
Okay, I'm in my sweatpants.
把食物端上来吧
Bring on the food.
怎么了   摩妮卡因为
What's the matter? Monica's all upset...
克朗克的事很难过
...because I sent Klunkers away.
所以呢  就把狗抱回来了  你会成为大英雄的
So? Bring the dog back. You're a hero.
对  我可以当大英雄  我可以那么做  可以
Yeah, I could be a hero. I could do that. I could. I could do...
万一他攻击我呢
What if it--? What if it attacks me?
钱德   他就像只大沙鼠
Chandler, it's like a big gerbil.
你不害怕吗
And that doesn't scare you?
罗斯   需要帮忙吗
Ross, you need some help?
你要帮我忙
From you?
好的   拜托你了
Yes, please.
首先   犹他州
First of all, Utah?
兄弟   你不能乱编州名
Dude, you can't just make stuff up.
我恨美国
I hate America.
游戏结束后   我发誓我要搬家
When I finish this game, I swear I am moving.
嘿   泰格还在跟警察谈   对
Hey. Tag still talking to the police? Yeah.
该死   我为什么要说话
Ugh, damn it. Why did I open my mouth?
"我暗恋你   我被你吸引"
"I have a crush on you. I'm attracted to you."
我知道   我吓坏他了
I know that I freaked him out.
如果你是那种口气  他一定吓坏了
If you said it like that, you probably did, yeah.
嘿   钱德在吗
Hey, is Chandler here?
不在   他去散步了
Uh, no, no, he went for a walk.
好了  你们不能告诉他啊   看看是谁回来了
Okay, well, you cannot tell him, but look who's back.
嗨   喔   不  不
Hi. Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
他去罗斯家把小狗带回来了
He went over to Ross' to bring the dog back here.
不  不  小狗不在那里呀
Oh, no, the dog's not going to be there.
你这么觉得啊
You think?
嗨   甜心
Hi, honey.
求求你  别对我生气
Please, please, please, don't be mad at me.
什么   为什么   等着瞧吧
What? Why would--? Shh. Wait and see.
或许我们会   或许我们不会
Maybe we will, maybe we won't.
我跑到罗斯家   想帮你把克朗克抱回来
Okay, I went over to Ross' apartment to bring back Klunkers, you know, for you...
我忘了关门   他一定是跑出去了
...and, ahem, I left the door open, and she must've gotten out.
我到处都找过了   找遍了整栋公寓   包括屋顶
And I looked everywhere, all over the apartment, including the roof.
对了  罗斯  你邻居在屋顶上种大麻
Which, FYI, Ross, one of your neighbors, growing weed.
我找不到他
I couldn't find him...
我真的很抱歉
...and I am so, so, so sorry.
但我知道  怎么样能让大家忘记痛苦
But I do know where we can all go ease the pain.
我们有好消息   看看谁回来了
We have good news. Look who's back.
嗨
Hi.
克朗克   我的天啊
Klunkers. Oh, my God.
没错   他是自己跑回来的   这是感恩节的奇迹啊
That's right. She came back all by herself. It's a Thanksgiving miracle.
真高兴能见到你
It is so good to see you.
他从罗斯家跑了回来
Yeah, she came all the way back from Ross' building.
他一定遇到了很多事
Oh, the things she must've seen.
他爬上消防梯
Then she climbed up the fire escape...
用他的小脚拍打窗户
...and she tapped on the window with her teeny little paw...
我们跑去开窗让他进来
...and we ran to let her in.
我说的太过火了   对吧
I went too far, didn't I?
我该在哪里就住口呢
When should I have stopped?
好了  或许这个游戏很难  是因为美国没有五十州
Okay, maybe this is so hard because there aren't 5O states.
我得告诉你一件事  我写出四十九州的州名
Let me tell you something. I have 49 states.
很全的答案了
Now, there are no more.
我想我应该可以吃点东西了
Now, I think I should be able to eat something.
随便你
It's up to you.
嗨   你还好吗   我很好
Oh, hi. How are you doing? I'm okay.
我得到警局去  指认嫌犯的照片
I gotta go down to the police station and look at mug shots.
谢谢你们邀请我来这里   秦格  你要走了吗
Thanks for having me over, you guys. Tag, you're going? Uh...
我们还没有机会好好谈一谈
We didn't, uh, get a chance to talk.
你说你是哪一州的人
So where did you say you're from again?
科罗拉多州   你真是没用
Colorado. Ah, what good are you?
听着  我想我们该谈谈   在阳台上发生的事
Look, urn, I think we should talk about what happened on the terrace.
好吧
Okay. Uh...
我不该说那些话的
I never should've said what I said.
我的感觉并不重要
You know what? It just doesn't matter how I feel.
我们一起工作   不应该有任何私人关系
We work together, so nothing could really ever happen between us.
星期一我想高高兴兴去上班   再也不提这件事了
What I would love is just to go to work on Monday and never talk about this again.
好了  星期一是个大日子  我们还有很多事要做
Okay? Big day, Monday. Lots to do.
我们应该还好吧
So we okay?
我一点都不好
Um, I'm not.
我就知道   我吓到你了   不   你没有
Oh, God, I knew it. I freaked you out. No, you didn't.
吓坏我的反而是
The only thing that freaked me out was you saying...
你说我们之间不该有关系
...that nothing could happen between us.
真的吗   对
Really? Yeah.
请不要因为我这么做   就炒我鱿鱼
So please don't fire me for doing this.
星期一我们得做的事少了一件
Okay, well, that's one less thing we have to do on Monday.
德拉瓦州
Delaware.
好吧   我要吃我的火鸡
All right. I want my turkey now.
没问题
You got it.
你重覆写了两次内华达州
You got Nevada twice.
我知道   好吧
I know. Yeah.